{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Noah","incorrectAnswers":["Isaac","Moses","Adam"],"question":"In the Bible who sent out a dove to find land?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Fresh Prince of Bel-Air","incorrectAnswers":["Family Matters","Full House","Seinfeld"],"question":"Which 1990s sitcom featured a well-to-do California family taking in a streetwise relative from Philadelphia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Gosling","incorrectAnswers":["A Caterpillar","A Joey","A Cub"],"question":"What is the word for a young goose?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Miguel de Cervantes","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Victor Hugo","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Novelas ejemplares ruth nailibeth'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Highbrow","incorrectAnswers":["Bearded","Moûstaché","Quiff"],"question":"Which of these words is used to refer to a very cultured activity?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Tempest","incorrectAnswers":["Othello","A Midsummer Night's Dream","Romeo and Juliet"],"question":"In which of Shakespeare's plays does the character 'Prospero' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Mary Had A Little Lamb","incorrectAnswers":["Twinkle Twinkle Little Star","Humpty Dumpty","Three Blind Mice"],"question":"Which nursery rhyme was the first gramophone recording?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"John Wayne","incorrectAnswers":["Jean-Claude Van Damme","Seth Rogen","John Turturro"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including The Longest Day and The Quiet Man?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bradley Cooper","incorrectAnswers":["Ryan Reynolds","Jim Carrey","Hugh Jackman"],"question":"Which Hollywood actor has starred in films including Guardians of the Galaxy and American Hustle?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Scooby Doo","incorrectAnswers":["Spongebob Squarepants","Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles","South Park"],"question":"In Which Cartoon Might You Encounter 'The Mystery Machine'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Memphis","incorrectAnswers":["Knoxville","Nashville","Dallas"],"question":"In which US City was Martin Luther King assassinated in 1968?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Drake","incorrectAnswers":["Kanye West","Lil Wayne","Lil Nas X"],"question":"Which hip-hop artist has the most Billboard Music Awards wins?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"You don't understand! I coulda had class. I coulda been a contender. I could've been somebody, instead of a bum, which is what I am.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"You’re going to go through life thinking that girls don’t like you because you’re a nerd. And I want you to know, from the bottom of my heart, that won’t be true. It’ll be because you’re an a**hole.\"","\"I know who I am. I’m the dude playing a dude disguised as another dude!\"","\"Plastics.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'On the Waterfront'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I am a golden god!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"My precious.\"","\"Made it, Ma! Top of the world!\"","\"The stuff that dreams are made of.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Almost Famous'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Dhaka","incorrectAnswers":["Vilnius","Rabat","Lusaka"],"question":"What is the capital city of Bangladesh?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Golden Eagle","incorrectAnswers":["Monarch Butterfly","Jaguar","Chihuahua"],"question":"What animal appears on the flag of Mexico?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Twelfth Night","incorrectAnswers":["Romeo & Juliette","Hamlet","The Taming of the Shrew"],"question":"Which Shakespeare play contains the line 'if music be the food of love play on''?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kathmandu","incorrectAnswers":["Tashkent","Gaborone","Gitega"],"question":"What is the capital city of Nepal?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Ever Fallen In Love","incorrectAnswers":["Smoke on the Water","Wish You Were Here","The Boys Are Back In Town"],"question":"Which Classic 70's Hit Features The Line \"And If I Start A Commotion I Run The Risk Of Losing You And That's Worse\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Soup ","incorrectAnswers":["Stew","Cured Meat","Vegetable"],"question":"Gazpacho is a type of what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","The Who"],"question":"Which British rock band released the song 'Flash', the theme tune to the film 'Flash Gordon'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Thailand","incorrectAnswers":["Vietnam","Laos","Cambodia"],"question":"Which Southeast Asian monarchy was never colonized by Europeans?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1982","incorrectAnswers":["1990","1971","1964"],"question":"In Which Year Did The Falklands Conflict Begin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Titanic","incorrectAnswers":["The Majestic","The Enormous","The Colossus"],"question":"Which British liner sank on its maiden voyage in 1912?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Michelin Star","incorrectAnswers":["North Star","Flavour Star","Prestige Star"],"question":"What Type Of Star Is Awarded To Restaurants Where The food Is Of Exceptional Quality?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Mike","incorrectAnswers":["Mambo","Mauritius","Mendip"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter M?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Dead Sea","incorrectAnswers":["Red Sea","Black Sea","Baltic Sea"],"question":"Which is the only sea below sea level?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nirvana","incorrectAnswers":["The Rolling Stones","Whitesnake","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which band did Kurt Cobain belong to?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"One","incorrectAnswers":["Blue","Eight","Black"],"question":"What does the word 'um' mean in Portuguese?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Doe","incorrectAnswers":["A Pen","A Mare","A Nanny"],"question":"A female deer is known as what?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Majuro","incorrectAnswers":["Funafuti","Santiago","Nouakchott"],"question":"What is the capital city of Marshall Islands?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The Nose","incorrectAnswers":["The Kidneys","The Skin","The Brain"],"question":"Which Part Of The Body Is Affected By Rhinitis?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Burkina Faso","incorrectAnswers":["Libya","Nigeria","Congo"],"question":"What is the name of the African country that was formerly known as The Republic of Upper Volta?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Amy Adams","incorrectAnswers":["Penélope Cruz","Emma Thompson","Kirsten Dunst"],"question":"Which actress has starred in both Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice and American Hustle?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"With great power comes great responsiblity.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I love lamp.\"","\"Which would be worse, to live a monster or die as a good man?\"","\"La-dee-da, la-dee-da.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Spider-Man'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"German Bread ","incorrectAnswers":["Belgian Wheat Beer","Dutch Cheese","Danish Butter"],"question":"What is pumpernickel?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"DNA","incorrectAnswers":["The Brain","Dark Matter","Beta Radiation"],"question":"What did Francis Crick and James Watson build a molecular model of in 1953?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Vertigo","incorrectAnswers":["Insomnia","Nausea","Headache"],"question":"Which of these is a movie directed by Alfred Hitchcock?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Franz Kafka","incorrectAnswers":["Émile Zola","Nathaniel Hawthorne","Leo Tolstoy"],"question":"Which author wrote 'In the Penal Colony'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Pacific Ocean","incorrectAnswers":["The Atlantic Ocean","The Indian Ocean","The Caribbean Sea"],"question":"Which surrounding body of water is represented by the blue triangle on the flag of the Solomon Islands?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Igor Stravinsky","incorrectAnswers":["Gustav Holst","Franz Schubert","Joseph Haydn"],"question":"Who Wrote \"The Firebird Suite\" & \"The Ebony Concerto\"? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the song 'Russian Roulette'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Darwin","incorrectAnswers":["Percy Bysshe Shelley","H. Rider Haggard","Robert Louis Stevenson"],"question":"Which author wrote 'On the Tendency of Species to form Varieties; and on the Perpetuation of Varieties and Species by Natural Means of Selection'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Oedipus","incorrectAnswers":["Jason","Hercules","Perseus"],"question":"In Greek mythology, who solved the riddle of the Sphinx?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Endocrine glands","incorrectAnswers":["Eccrine glands","Salivary glands","Mammary glands"],"question":"In the human body, what is the name given to glands responsible for producing hormones?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Boxing","incorrectAnswers":["Cricket","Rugby Union","Ice Hockey"],"question":"With which sport is Manny Pacquiao associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Mauritius","incorrectAnswers":["Afghanistan","Cuba","Greece"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Dholl Puri?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hydroponics","incorrectAnswers":["Horticulture","Apedology","Anapedics"],"question":"What Is The Method Of Growing Plants Without Soil?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Purple","Yellow","Blue"],"question":"Which colour has highest wavelength in the visible spectrum?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"John Lennon","incorrectAnswers":["Paul McCartney","George Harrison","Ringo Starr"],"question":"Which member of The Beatles famously claimed to be 'More popular than Jesus'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Cars","incorrectAnswers":["Heart And Soul","I Know What Boys Like","Somebody's Watching Me"],"question":"What song did Gary Numan have a hit with in 1980?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Gloria Jones","incorrectAnswers":["The Velvet Underground","Pulp","Johnny Rivers"],"question":"The song 'Tainted Love' had a well-known cover by Soft Cell, but who recorded the original?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"North by Northwest","incorrectAnswers":["Dr. Strangelove or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb","Beauty and the Beast","Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'An executive goes on the run after being mistaken for a government agent.'","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Heart","incorrectAnswers":["Soul","Blood","Eyes"],"question":"What part of the body does carditis affect?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Rio de Janeiro","incorrectAnswers":["Brasilia","Salvador","Recife"],"question":"What is the name of the second-most populous city in Brazil, following Sao Paulo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Austria and Italy ","incorrectAnswers":["Estonia and Latvia","Iran and Iraq","Morocco and Tunisia"],"question":"What two countries do Tyroleans come from? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Halle Berry","incorrectAnswers":["Frances Fisher","Salma Hayek","Rachel Weisz"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Storm in the X-Men series of films?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Des'ree","incorrectAnswers":["Gary Numan","Edwyn Collins","Brownsville Station"],"question":"'You Gotta Be' was a one hit wonder in 1995 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Bull","incorrectAnswers":["A Dog","A Tiercel","A Hob"],"question":"A male shark is known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hg","incorrectAnswers":["KOH","NaCI","CaCO3"],"question":"What is the chemical formula for mercury?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Mexico","incorrectAnswers":["France","Argentina","England"],"question":"Which country hosted the 1986 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Soccer","incorrectAnswers":["Motorsports","Cricket","Rugby"],"question":"Which sport is played at The FA Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Easter Sunday","incorrectAnswers":["Christmas Day","Good Friday","Christmas Eve"],"question":"On which day was the resurrection of Christ?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Maggie Smith","incorrectAnswers":["Kathy Bates","Sandra Bæ Hovedr","Kirsten Dunst"],"question":"Which actress has starred in films including Gosford Park and Downton Abbey?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dead Man's Chest","incorrectAnswers":["Curse of the Black Pearl","At World's End","On Stranger Tides"],"question":"What was the name of the second 'Pirates of the Caribbean' movie?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Offspring","incorrectAnswers":["Styx","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which punk band from the United States released the studio album 'Smash'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Yellow River","incorrectAnswers":["The Mekong River","The Yangtze River","The Congo River"],"question":"What river is known as China's sorrow because of its flooding?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Beaker","incorrectAnswers":["Ernie","Oscar","Scooter"],"question":"What is the name of the lab assistant who appeared with Dr. Bunsen Honeydew on \"The Muppet Show\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"West Side Story","incorrectAnswers":["The Sound of Music","Oklahoma!","Grease"],"question":"Which famous musical features the song 'I Feel Pretty'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Soil","incorrectAnswers":["Childrens' behaviour and development","Teaching","Flying Reptiles"],"question":"Pedology is the study of ______ ?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Snorri Sturluson","incorrectAnswers":["Sebastian Brant","Agatha Christie","Rainer Maria Rilke"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Heimskringla'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Alcatraz","incorrectAnswers":["Angel Island","The Galapagos Islands","Plymouth Rock"],"question":"Which island, also known as 'The Rock', is a prime stop on a San Francisco tour?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Alice Cooper","incorrectAnswers":["Thin Lizzy","Aerosmith","Fleetwood Mac"],"question":"Who had a hit with School's Out in 1972?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nine Inch Nails","incorrectAnswers":["Nirvana","The Clash","Blink 182"],"question":"Which band was Trent Reznor the lead vocalist for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Triangle","incorrectAnswers":["A Square","A Circle","A Rectangle"],"question":"What type of shape might be obtuse or isosceles?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Public Enemy","incorrectAnswers":["Rain Man","The Silence of the Lambs","All About Eve"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Tom Powers'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Absinthe ","incorrectAnswers":["Gin","Port","Whisky"],"question":"Which drink, which has been illegal but is being imported once again, is made from the leaves of the wormwood plant?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Gemini","incorrectAnswers":["Taurus","Leo","Scorpio"],"question":"Which dual-natured astrological sign is associated with Castor & Pollux and means two-faced?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Henry VIII","incorrectAnswers":["Charles I","William the Conqueror","James III"],"question":"Who was the father of Queen Elizabeth I of England?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The llama","incorrectAnswers":["The Panther","The Iguana","The Chimpanzee"],"question":"In Incan mythology, which animal warned about the impending flood?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Rolling Stones","incorrectAnswers":["McFly","Delirious?","Depeche Mode"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Brown Sugar'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"James","incorrectAnswers":["Marshall","Theodore","Thomas"],"question":"What were the first names of US presidents Madison, Monroe, Polk, and Garfield?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"One morning I shot an elephant in my pajamas. How he got in my pajamas, I don't know.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Soylent Green is people!\"","\"I’m going to have to science the s*** out of this.\"","\"Toto, I've a feeling we're not in Kansas anymore.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Animal Crackers'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Asbestos","incorrectAnswers":["Fiberglass","Carbon fiber","Reinforced concrete"],"question":"What is the name of the fibrous mineral formerly used to make fireproof articles?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1983","incorrectAnswers":["1978","1988","1993"],"question":"In which year was Scarface released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jules Verne","incorrectAnswers":["Victor Hugo","Alphonse Daudet","Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Around the World in Eighty Days'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A woman tries to warn anyone who will listen about the merciless space predators that attacked her.","incorrectAnswers":["24 hours in the lives of three young men the day after a violent riot.","The merciless rivalry between Formula One rivals James Hunt and Niki Lauda.","Explorers travel through a wormhole in space in an attempt to ensure humanity's survival."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Aliens?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"grasshoppers and crickets","incorrectAnswers":["the study and treatment of diseases of the urogenital tract","the biosphere and its relations to the lithosphere and atmosphere","male health and disease"],"question":"What is Orthopterology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"1945","incorrectAnswers":["1935","1955","1965"],"question":"In which year did the Volkswagen Beetle make its first appearance?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Adidas","incorrectAnswers":["Nike","Puma","Reebok"],"question":"Which sports brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'Impossible is Nothing'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Deodoro da Fonseca","incorrectAnswers":["Juscelino Kubitschek","Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva","Fernando Henrique Cardoso"],"question":"Who was the first president of Brazil?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sino-Tibetan","incorrectAnswers":["Austronesian","Uralic","Niger–Congo"],"question":"The language 'Southern Min' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Carnivorous","incorrectAnswers":["Trap","Pitcher","Belljar"],"question":"What is the term for the group of plants that catch and digest insects?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Scorpions","incorrectAnswers":["Rammstein","Sodom","U.D.O."],"question":"Which German rock band released the song 'Rock You Like a Hurricane'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Battlestar Galactica","incorrectAnswers":["Westworld","The Terminator","RoboCop"],"question":"What 2005-2009 TV show featured Cylons and cyborgs?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Denis Diderot","Ludwig Wittgenstein"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'We live in the best of all possible worlds'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Sun Also Rises","incorrectAnswers":["Winnie the Pooh","Gone With the Wind","The Horse's Mouth"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Jake Barnes'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1973","incorrectAnswers":["1930","1891","1990"],"question":"In What year did British Honduras become Belize?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Neville Chamberlain","incorrectAnswers":["Winston Churchill","Anthony Eden","Clement Atlee"],"question":"Who was the British Prime Minister at the outbreak of the Second World War?","difficulty":"medium"},